<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>RimSynapse - NVIDIA Tool</name>
    <author>RimSynapse Team</author>
    <packageId>RimSynapse.NVIDIATool</packageId>
    <url>https://github.com/RimSynapse/NVIDIA-Tool</url>
    <modVersion>0.5.1</modVersion>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>RimSynapse.Core</packageId>
            <displayName>RimSynapse - Core</displayName>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/RimSynapse/Core/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/3760829776</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>RimSynapse.Core</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <description>
RimSynapse - NVIDIA Tool
Official Wiki and Documentation: https://github.com/RimSynapse/NVIDIA-Tool/wiki

Real-Time GPU Monitoring and LLM Performance Dashboard for RimSynapse.

This developer and power-user tool provides a comprehensive overview of your local GPU's health, VRAM usage, and LLM request performance — all rendered directly inside RimWorld's UI.

--- Core Systems ---
- Live GPU Monitoring: Reads NVIDIA GPU stats via nvidia-smi in real-time. Displays VRAM usage, GPU temperature, utilization percentage, and power draw.
- VRAM Breakdown: Shows a detailed breakdown of estimated VRAM consumption: model size, KV cache, context window, and overhead. Helps you understand exactly where your GPU memory is going.
- VRAM Warnings: Proactive alerts when your GPU is approaching VRAM limits, with recommendations for model sizes and context window adjustments.
- Request Metrics: Tracks every LLM request made by RimSynapse mods — response times, token counts, throughput (tokens/second), and queue depth. Identifies bottlenecks in your AI pipeline.
- In-Game Overlay HUD: A toggleable on-screen overlay that displays GPU stats, request queue status, and active model information without opening any menus.
- Developer Tools Window: A comprehensive debug window with tabs for GPU stats, request history, VRAM analysis, and configuration. Essential for mod developers building on RimSynapse.

--- Toolbar Integration ---
- Quick Toggle: A toolbar button lets you instantly toggle the GPU overlay and open the developer tools window.

--- Default Settings (adjustable in-game) ---
  Overlay Enabled:               false  (Toggle the on-screen GPU HUD)
  nvidia-smi Poll Interval:      2000ms (How often GPU stats are refreshed)
  Request History Length:         100    (Number of recent LLM requests to keep in the metrics log)

--- Changelog ---
v0.4.0
- Updated to support RimSynapse Core v0.4.0 (Multi-provider routing and Image generation).

--- Compatibility Matrix ---
- Royalty DLC: Compatible
- Ideology DLC: Compatible
- Biotech DLC: Compatible
- Anomaly DLC: Compatible

--- Requirements ---
- RimSynapse Core (Must be loaded before this mod)
- An NVIDIA GPU with nvidia-smi available on PATH (automatically detected).

--- Note ---
This tool is optional and purely diagnostic. It does not affect gameplay. It is intended for users who want to monitor their hardware while running local LLMs alongside RimWorld.

--- Support the Project ---
Buy me a coffee: https://buymeacoffee.com/archdukejim
    </description>
</ModMetaData>
